<idea-plugin>
    <id>com.github.brannow.phpstormmcp</id>
    <name>MCP Control</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/brannow/idea-mcp-control">Benjamin Rannow</vendor>
    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <b>0.5.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Breakpoint mutations (add, update, remove) now return the full breakpoint list with (new)/(updated) highlights</li>
            <li>Batch operations: breakpoint_add accepts comma-separated locations, breakpoint_update accepts comma-separated IDs</li>
            <li>Method breakpoint detection: adding a breakpoint on a function definition line is blocked with guidance to add manually</li>
            <li>Stack trace collapsing: 3+ consecutive library frames collapsed by default, expand_stack parameter to override</li>
            <li>Session-breakpoint cross-reference: session_list shows which breakpoint a paused session is at</li>
            <li>Smarter session switch detection: terminated sessions auto-track the next session instead of blocking</li>
            <li>Evaluate tool description clarifies frame #0 limitation (xdebug constraint)</li>
            <li>Fix: circular reference false positives on arrays with size info (e.g. array[7])</li>
            <li>Cleaner output: "Current breakpoints:" header on remove/partial-failure responses</li>
            <li>Leaner evaluate output: removed redundant source position header</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.4.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>New tool: breakpoint_add_exception — break on any PHP exception class by name</li>
            <li>Short name lookup with disambiguation (RuntimeException → lists all matches if ambiguous)</li>
            <li>Only classes extending \Exception or \Error are accepted</li>
            <li>Exception breakpoints work with existing breakpoint_list, breakpoint_update, and breakpoint_remove</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.3.2</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Rebranding: MCP Hub → MCP Control</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.3.1</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Fix: .mcp.json installer now includes required "type": "http" field</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.3.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>New tool: debug_console — read stdout/stderr from the debug session's console (useful for Docker/remote PHP processes)</li>
            <li>Fix: stopping a session now auto-activates the next alive session instead of leaving a dead tab focused</li>
            <li>Smarter session errors: when the active session ends but other sessions exist, the error lists them with guidance to use session_activate</li>
            <li>Cleaner session switch alert messages</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.2.1</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Show plugin version in tool window status line</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.2.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>New tool: session_activate — switch active debug session (like clicking a debug tab)</li>
            <li>Removed session_id parameter from all debug tools — simpler API, fewer tokens</li>
            <li>Session switch detection: agent gets an alert if the user or IDE switches the active session unexpectedly</li>
            <li>MCP server version now matches the plugin version</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.1</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Fix: Settings page now visible under Settings > Tools > MCP Control</li>
        </ul>
        <b>0.1.0</b>
        <ul>
            <li>Initial release</li>
            <li>13 MCP tools: breakpoints, sessions, navigation, inspection</li>
            <li>Tool window with activity log, start/stop, settings</li>
            <li>One-click .mcp.json installation</li>
            <li>Configurable port and auto-start per project</li>
        </ul>
    ]]></change-notes>
    <description><![CDATA[
        <p>MCP server that gives AI agents access to IDE features they can't get from the command line.</p>

        <p>Agents can read files and run terminals on their own.
        They can't set breakpoints, step through code, or inspect variables.
        MCP Control exposes these IDE-only capabilities as MCP tools.</p>

        <h3>15 tools across 4 categories</h3>

        <b>Breakpoints</b> (work without an active debug session)
        <ul>
            <li>list, add, update, remove — with batch support (comma-separated)</li>
            <li>Exception breakpoints — pause on any PHP exception class</li>
            <li>Conditions, log expressions, suspend control</li>
            <li>Method breakpoint detection — prevents wrong breakpoint type</li>
        </ul>

        <b>Session management</b>
        <ul>
            <li>List active debug sessions, stop one or all</li>
            <li>Switch active session (all debug tools operate on the active session)</li>
        </ul>

        <b>Navigation</b> (requires paused session)
        <ul>
            <li>Step over / into / out / continue</li>
            <li>Run to a specific line</li>
            <li>Every step returns a snapshot: source context, variables, call stack (library frames auto-collapsed)</li>
        </ul>

        <b>Inspection</b> (requires paused session)
        <ul>
            <li>Full debug snapshot (source + variables + stack trace)</li>
            <li>Expand variables to any depth (circular references detected)</li>
            <li>Switch stack frames and inspect variables at that scope</li>
            <li>Evaluate PHP expressions with side effects ($bar = 'new value')</li>
            <li>Read console output (stdout/stderr) — works with Docker/remote processes</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Setup</h3>
        <ol>
            <li>Open the MCP Control tool window (bottom panel)</li>
            <li>Click "Install .mcp.json" to configure your MCP client</li>
            <li>Start the server</li>
        </ol>
        <p>Works with Claude Code, Cursor, Claude Desktop, and any other MCP client.
        Configurable port, optional auto-start per project.</p>

        <h3>How debugging works</h3>
        <p>You start debug sessions in PhpStorm as usual. The agent interacts with them
        through MCP tools: setting breakpoints, stepping through code, inspecting state.
        You both see the same debug session. Pair debugging with an AI.</p>
    ]]></description>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.modules.xdebugger</depends>
    <depends>com.jetbrains.php</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <notificationGroup
            id="MCP Control"
            displayType="BALLOON"/>
        <projectConfigurable
            parentId="tools"
            instance="com.github.brannow.phpstormmcp.settings.McpSettingsConfigurable"
            id="com.github.brannow.phpstormmcp.settings"
            displayName="MCP Control"
            nonDefaultProject="true"/>
        <toolWindow
            id="MCP Control"
            anchor="bottom"
            icon="/icons/mcpStatusInactive.svg"
            factoryClass="com.github.brannow.phpstormmcp.toolwindow.McpToolWindowFactory"/>
        <postStartupActivity
            implementation="com.github.brannow.phpstormmcp.startup.McpAutoStartActivity"/>
    </extensions>
</idea-plugin>
